Teiko Middle School
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
Who's gone soft?
（黄瀬）
誰がいつ丸くなったって？
No you don't!
（木吉(きよし)）させるか！
And that's Aomine's change of pace!
（木吉）
青峰と同じチェンジオブペース！
（黄瀬）えいっ
（日向(ひゅうが)）うわっ
（火神(かがみ)）うっ！
（火神）
赤司のエンペラーアイまで…
He can even copy Akashi's Emperor Eye?
The Vanishing Drive!
（笠松(かさまつ)）バニシングドライブ？
（黒子(くろこ)）あ…
（日向）紫原でも止められなかった
無敵のシュートが…
Not even Murasakibara could
stop that invincible shot,
and he blocked it?
ブロックされた
The True Light
（黄瀬）えいっ
Kise's not stopping!
（観客１）黄瀬が止まらねえ！
（観客２）
開始早々 攻守で１人無双
Since the game started, no one's
been able to touch him!
They're already 13 points ahead!
Kaijo
Seirin
一気に13点差！
It's like fighting the whole
Generation of Miracles at once.
（火神）“キセキの世代”
５人いっぺんに—
相手してるようなもんだ
ヤベエ マジで手がつけられねえ
Shit. He's out of control.
And it's only been three minutes?
しかもまだ３分!?
パーフェクトコピーの
持続時間からいって—
His Perfect Copy will last
another two minutes, too.
あと２分は
これが続くのかよ!?
（黄瀬）ハァ
あー しんど
Man, this is rough.
I'm taking a break.
とりあえず ちょっと休憩っス
What?
（火神）なっ
（黄瀬）やっぱ あの人らの—
Copying them is really tiring.
コピーは しんどいっスわ
I can't be falling over
at the start of the game.
始まってすぐ
ぶっ倒れるわけにもいかねえし—
The game's just getting started.
試合は まだまだこれから
I need to save some fun for later.
お楽しみを後にも
取っとかないとね
けど ま
目的は十分 果たせたっスよ
But I got what I wanted.
We're in control of the game.
主導権 もらった
（日向）最悪だ
This is terrible.
Uh-oh. They're losing already.
（紫原）
あーらら いきなりやられたね
But...
（紫原）でもさ…
（氷室(ひむろ)）ん？
Kise-chin's Perfect Copy
is certainly impressive.
確かに黄瀬ちんの—
パーフェクトコピーは
すごいけど—
終盤 もう一度使うにしても—
But he only has two more minutes
to use at the end of the game.
残り２分に減ったんだし
結局 早いか遅いかってだけじゃん
It'll happen sooner or later.
（氷室）いや…
そんな単純な話でもないさ
No. It's not that simple.
Huh?
Every game has its own flow.
試合には流れってものがある
Their surprise attack succeeded.
奇襲は成功した
そしてその効果は続く
It'll keep affecting the game.
恐らく それこそ
海常(かいじょう)の本当の狙いだ
That was probably Kaijo's true aim.
（日向）えいっ
Damn it!
（日向）くそっ １秒でも早く
差を縮めたい時に
We need to be closing the
gap as quickly as possible!
（伊月(いづき)）ドンマイ 日向！
（日向）ああ！
Don't worry about it, Hyuga!
Yeah!
Kagami!
（伊月）火神！
（黄瀬）
フルドライブからのフェイダウェイ
A fadeaway out of a full drive.
また懐かしい技っスね
でも…
Another old move.
But...
What?
They failed another attack.
連続で攻撃失敗
So this is what you meant.
室(むろ)ちんが言ってたの
こういうことね
Yeah. They're completely off balance.
（氷室）ああ
完全に浮き足立ってしまったな
恐らく誠凛は当初
先行逃げきりを目指したはずだ
Seirin initially planned to
establish a lead and hold it.
But after that unexpected surprise
attack, they've fallen far behind.
ところが実際は
予想外の奇襲を受け—
先行どころか いきなり
大差をつけられてしまった
They want to close the gap.
一刻も早く点差を縮めたい
But their impatience dulls their
attacks, leading to mistakes.
だが焦りは攻撃を単調にし
ミスを呼ぶ
このままだと
攻撃は空回る一方だぞ
At this rate, their attacks
will keep failing.
Member change.
（リコ）メンバーチェンジ
降旗(ふりはた)君 出番よ
Furihata-kun.
You're in.
What?
Izuki-kun!
（リコ）伊月君
Calm down, calm down, calm down.
（降旗）落ち着け 落ち着け
落ち着け
ずっと願ってきたじゃないか
You've been wanting this for a long time.
You guys always get to play,
（降旗）火神や黒子は
いつも試合出てるからいいけど—
オレたちだって
たまには試合に出たいっつうか
but sometimes we want to play, too.
（降旗）
ついにその日が来たんだ
That day has finally come.
I'm okay.
大丈夫
（降旗）おちつ… うう うわー
Calm down...
コートに入ると全然違う
It feels totally different
once I'm on the court!
黒子や先輩たちは
こんな中でプレーしてたのか
Kuroko and the upperclassmen
have been playing like this?
頼むぞ マーク４番な
We're counting on you.
Your mark is No. 4.
Huh? What?
（黄瀬）まさか
ここまで隠してきた秘密兵器—
Is he a secret weapon they've
been hiding until now?
I guess not.
は… ねーか
I don't know what the coach is
thinking, but do your best, Furi.
カントクの考えは分かんねえけど
頑張ろうぜ フリ
Do your best?
（降旗）ガンバローゼ？ 英語？
Is that English? Can I eat it?
何 それ おいしいの？
Let's do our best, Furihata-kun.
頑張りましょう 降旗君
あれ？
Huh?
（福田(ふくだ)）黒子の姿も見えていない
He doesn't even see Kuroko...
（小金井(こがねい)）マジ 大丈夫なのか？
Is he going to be okay?
What? They sent a petrified first year?
（笠松）んだぁ？ 出てきたの
ガチガチの１年坊かよ？
I can't do this!
（降旗）無理だ 怖(こえ)えー
It's too scary!
They subbed in a first year point guard.
（武内(たけうち)）この局面で出してきた
１年ポイントガードか
What kind of plays will he make?
一体 どんなプレーを？
（ホイッスル）
（日向）いくぞ！
Let's go!
落ち着けー！
Calm down!
（福田）うわー
（河原(かわはら)）しっかりしろ フリ！
Keep it together, Furi!
Thanks, I guess!
まあ 一応…
ありがとよ
What?
（笠松）うっ しまった
この透明少年
Shit. This invisible kid...
すみません
少し待ってください
Sorry. Give us a minute.
He's still nervous.
まだ緊張しているようなので
ああ？ いや知るか！
What?
That's not my problem!
Furihata-kun!
（黒子）降旗君
大丈夫です
ボクのデビュー戦は—
It's okay.
In my first game, I tripped
and got a bloody nose.
転んで鼻血出しましたから
Kuroko...
黒子…
（降旗）マジで？
（黒子）マジです
Seriously?
Seriously.
カントク 大丈夫なんですか？
Coach, are you sure about this?
あいつ ホント
人一倍ビビリで…
He's the biggest wuss around.
That's why you subbed him in, right?
だからいいんじゃないか
てことだろ？
ビビリは短所じゃないさ
His cowardice isn't a weakness.
There are some things only a coward can do.
臆病だからこそ
できることもある
That's right. Just watch.
そう まあ見てなさい
（笠松）まだ全然 ガチガチだぜ
He's still stiff as a board.
つーか
仮に緊張してなくても—
Even if he weren't nervous,
I doubt he'd work against us.
正直 とても通用するとは
思えねえな
Hey!
（火神）はい！
It's Kagami!
（観客）
火神だ ワンオンワンか！
It's a one-on-one!
次は外さねえ
勝負だ 黄瀬！
I'm not missing the next one!
Let's go, Kise!
ハッ 望むところっスよ
Bring it on!
（降旗）火神 ストップ！
Kagami, stop!
おち… おち… おちちゅけ
C-Calm... Calm down!
（火神）はあ？ なっ
いや オマエが落ち着けよ
Huh? What?
You're the one who needs to calm down!
何だ 来ないんスか？
You're not coming?
うっせえ ひとまず仕切り直しだ
Shut up.
We have to get this back under control.
This is...
（武内）これは…
誠凛の雰囲気が変わった
Seirin feels different.
さっきまでとは一転
パスを回して慎重な攻め
They're passing the ball around
and attacking carefully.
I see.
なるほど
Their goal was to slow the pace down.
（笠松）目的はペースダウンか
しかも—
But they're not just taking it easy.
ただ のんびりしてるって
わけでもなさそうだ
さっき火神が行こうとしたとき—
Kobori and Hayakawa were quick to respond
小堀(こぼり)と早川(はやかわ)の備えが早かった
when they thought Kagami was coming.
Even if he made it past Kise,
they would've caught him immediately.
仮に黄瀬を抜いても
すぐヘルプに捕まっていたはず
This guy...
こいつ…
Coach, is this...
（小金井）カントク これって…
（リコ）ええ
ビビリってのは—
Yes.
Cowardly is just another way to say careful.
言いかえればそれだけ
用心深いってことよ
つまり ムチャな攻めは
絶対にしない
In other words, cowards
never attack recklessly.
He's the perfect player when you
want to change the pace of the game.
今回みたいに
ペースを変えたいときに—
彼ほど うってつけな
選手はいないわ
（降旗）あの…
出たらオレ 何をすれば？
Uh, what should I do on the court?
何も
Nothing special.
（リコ）いつもどおりでいいわよ
（降旗）え？
Do what you always do.
（リコ）いつもどおり
時間たっぷり使って—
Take your time and play at
your pace like you always do.
あなたのペースで
やってくれればいいわ
けど 慎重なだけじゃダメよ
But you can't just be careful.
It may seem obvious, but you have
to take it to the finish line.
当たり前だけど
ちゃんとフィニッシュまでいくこと
（降旗）と言っても どうすれば…
Yeah, but what should I do?
バカね 何言ってるのよ
Don't be stupid. What are you talking about?
You have teammates.
チームメイトがいるでしょーが
Rely on them as much as you need to.
遠慮せず
ガンガン頼ればいいのよ
（日向）えいっ
Kaijo
Seirin
（日向）よーし
（木吉）ナイスパスだ フリ
All right!
Nice pass, Furi!
Looks like you're starting to loosen up.
緊張 ほぐれてきたみたいだな
（降旗）決まった
We did it.
（日向）くっ まずった
I messed up!
中途半端なところで
ドリブル止められちまった
He stopped me before I could get anywhere!
（降旗）キャプテン！
Captain!
（氷室）12番の彼は目立たないが
いい動きをしてるな
No. 12 doesn't stand out
much, but he moves well.
うまくサポートして
味方を動かしやすくしている
By supporting his teammates well,
he allows them to move around freely.
I sensed it during their last attack,
but that first year point guard...
（笠松）さっきの
攻めのときも感じたが—
あの １年ポイントガード
He compensates for mistakes and
avoids dangerous situations.
ミスを拾ってピンチを避ける
とにかく 味方を助けるのが
うまいって感じだ
He's good at assisting his allies.
（福田）だー キツー
（降旗）死ぬー
This is rough!
I'm going to die!
（福田）先輩たちは？
Where are the upperclassmen?
They're staying late to practice.
（降旗）まだ残って練習するって
（福田）ええ？
ホントに同じ人間かよ
Are they really human?
（河原）なあ
（降旗･福田）えっ？
Hey.
Huh?
オレ…
I'm thinking of quitting the team.
（河原）バスケ部 辞めようかな
（福田）なっ
What?
（降旗）何言ってるんだよ 急に
頑張ればきっと…
Where did that come from?
If you work hard, I'm sure...
I like basketball, but...
（河原）バスケは好きだよ
けど…
火神や黒子は もちろん—
Kagami, Kuroko,
先輩たちも
やっぱり みんなすごいよ
and all the upperclassmen are amazing.
I can barely keep up with
them during practice.
練習にも
ついていくのが精いっぱいで—
オレなんかじゃ
どんなに頑張っても—
No matter how hard I try,
I don't think I can play in a game.
試合になんて
とても無理な気がする
Kawahara...
河原…
I've actually
実はオレも…
同じこと 考えたことあるよ
thought the same thing.
Everyone thinks the same
thing when they see Kagami.
火神とか見てりゃ 誰だって思うよ
モノが違うって
That he's cut from a different cloth.
But watching Kuroko, I think something else.
けど 黒子見てると思うんだ
He's still amazing,
あいつもやっぱ
すげえんだけど—
オレでも 何かできることが
あるんじゃないかって
but maybe there's something I can do, too.
もし 最後まで
ベンチだったとしても—
Even if I ride the bench until the end,
I still want to play
basketball with the guys.
オレ やっぱりみんなと
バスケやってたい
辞めたら たぶん後悔する
I'd probably regret quitting.
えいっ
（日向）うおー 速い
They're fast!
We can intercept the pass!
カットできる もらった！
It's ours!
（黒子）えいっ
（森山(もりやま)）なっ
What?
Kuroko...
（森山）黒子…
行けー！
Go!
Nice shot, Furi!
（火神）ナイッシュ！ フリ
I wasn't expecting this ambush.
（森山）まさか
あんな伏兵がいるとはな
（早川）でも もうそおそお
交代すうでしょ
But they'll sub him out soon, right?
（武内）うむ そして交代しても
穴は変わらん
Yes.
And even if they do,
it won't change their weakness.
誠凛で一番弱い所は そこだ
It's Seirin's greatest weakness.
We'll focus our attacks
第２クオーターは—
around Kasamatsu even more
during the second quarter.
今以上に 笠松中心で攻める
うっす
Yes, sir.
I'm counting on you.
期待してるっス
（笠松）言われんでもやってやるよ
（黄瀬）いってー
You don't have to tell me!
Ow...
Furihata-kun, you're out.
（リコ）降旗君は ここで交代よ
（リコ）グッジョブ！
（降旗）あっ はい
Good job!
Okay!
Izuki-kun, you're up next.
（リコ）次からは伊月君
よろしくね
おけ持ってオーケー キタコレ！
I'm okay to go-kay.
Nice one.
さて
Now that we're back on our feet...
（リコ）地に足ついたところで
（伊月）無視!?
No response?
試合前に決めたプラン いくわよ
We'll go with the plan we
established before the game.
We've got something this
time to double our strength.
以前の練習試合では いなかった
ウチの一番の戦力倍増要素
鉄平中心で攻めるわよ
We'll focus our attacks around Teppei.
うん 任せろ
Leave it to me.
（笠松）うっ やはり来たか
I knew this was coming.
Come on!
来い！
（小堀）またか ゴール下から
パスをさばくパターン
Again!
He's passing from under the net!
Damn it!
くそっ
Don't worry, Kobori!
ドンマイ 小堀
オフェンス！
Offense!
A center showdown...
センター対決
誠凛にとっては一番勝率が高い
It's Seirin's greatest chance of winning.
They're going for the mismatch.
ミスマッチをついてきたな
It looks that way.
みたいだね けどさ—
But isn't this more obvious?
こっちのほうが
もっとあからさまじゃない？
（氷室）アイソレーションだ
Isolation, huh?
（木吉）笠松の
ペネトレートスペースを作った
They created space for Kasamatsu
to penetrate the key.
つまり ワンオンワンか
In other words, they want a one-on-one.
That first-year did his best,
but he's still only a first year.
（笠松）さっきの１年坊も
頑張っちゃいたが—
しょせん まだ１年だ
After that underwhelming performance,
I'm not holding back.
もの足りなかった分
思いっきりいかせてもらうぜ
Look closely.
（伊月）よく見ろ
速さじゃかなわない
He's way faster than you.
先を読め！
Predict his movements.
Left...
左… いや—
No, right!
右だ！
What?
そんな 読みは合ってた
なのに！
My prediction was right! So how...
（日向）ウソだろ
それでも追いつけない!?
You're kidding, right?
He still can't keep up?
（木吉）行かさん！
That's as far as you go!
（海常応援団）いいぞ いいぞ
笠松！ いいぞ いいぞ 笠松！
Go, go, Kasamatsu!
I'm not finished yet.
まだまだだな
（伊月）くっ 速い
He's fast.
“キセキの世代”を除けば
今までやった選手の中で最速だ
Aside from the Generation of Miracles,
he's the fastest opponent we've faced.
（日向）伊月
Izuki!
たぶん この先
同じパターンでガンガンくんぞ
They'll probably keep attacking like this.
They're assuming they'll pass you.
相手は まずオマエを抜くのを
前提に考えてる
In other words, they think
you're our weakest player.
要は現状 うちでは
オマエが一番ナメられてる
Yeah, I know.
ああ… 分かってる
（火神）ちょ キャプテン
いきなりキツくね？ ですよ
Captain, isn't that a little harsh?
What? Don't be so easy on him, moron!
ああ オマエこそいきなり
優しくすんな ダアホ
Izuki started playing his
second year of grade school.
伊月がバスケ始めたのは
小２のミニバスからだ
オレらの中で
一番キャリア長(なげ)えんだぞ
He's been playing longer than any of us.
心配しなくても このまま
へこたれるタマじゃねえよ
Don't worry.
This isn't enough to get him down.
No one's put more into basketball than him.
バスケに懸けた思いは誠凛一(いち)さ
頑張れなんて 言うだけやぼだ
Encouraging him is senseless.
Shit!
（火神）しまった！
（日向）戻れ！
Go back!
悪いがオマエじゃ止められねえ
Sorry, but you can't stop me.
One more time! One more time, please!
（伊月）もう１回 もう１回頼む
（小金井）ちょっ…
まだやんの？ 伊月
You want to keep going, Izuki?
I'm nearly there.
（伊月）つかめそうなんだ
景虎(かげとら)さんから教わった技
I nearly have the technique
Kagetora-san taught me.
オレは不器用だから
１つ技を覚えるのにも—
Since I'm so clumsy,
it takes me far more practice
to learn a single ability.
人の何倍も練習しなきゃならない
だったらできるまで
何倍でもやるしかないだろ
I just have to keep practicing
until I can do it.
Izuki!
（小金井）伊月！
This is it.
キタ コレ
イーグル… スピア！
Eagle Spear!
（笠松）何？
フルドライブ直後の—
What?
He waited until my defenses
were lowest, just after my drive...
一番 無防備な瞬間を狙って…
（小堀）イーグルアイを使って
後ろ向きのままバックチップ!?
And used his Eagle Eye to tip
the ball behind his back?
（森山）体の向きを変えない分
速度は格段に上がる
Not changing the direction he's facing
dramatically increases his speed.
But is that even possible?
だが そんなことが可能なのか？
All right!
よーし
カッとなってナイスカット
Mad men make mad interceptions!
Shut up, Izuki!
（日向）黙れ 伊月
謝るぜ
I apologize.
Honestly, I underestimated you, Izuki Shun.
正直 ちょっとナメてたわ
伊月 俊(しゅん)
Well, I'm more than just a pun master.
そりゃ ただの
ダジャレがうまい人と—
思われたら困るんで
What? Puns?
（笠松）は？ ダジャレ？
いつ言った？
When did you make any?
通じてなかった？
You didn't notice?
The pressure is incredible.
すごいプレッシャーだ
抜かれるのを承知で前に出ている
He's not backing down,
even though he knows he'll pass him.
Don't falter!
ひるむな！
抜いてやれ 笠松
Pass him, Kasamatsu!
If I pour all my nerves into it,
I should be able
（笠松）全神経を注いだ
ドライブなら出せるはずだ
to go fast enough to outrun his tip.
さっきのバックチップでも
追いつけない速さを だが…
But...
（武内）笠松の武器は外からの
攻撃と速さを生かしたドライブ
Kasamatsu's strengths are his
outside attacks and quick drives.
If his opponent approaches him
to prevent a shot, he drives.
相手がシュートを警戒して
近づけばドライブ
ドライブを警戒して
離れればシュート
If they back away to prevent
a drive, he shoots.
最もオーソドックス
かつ 強力なスタイルの１つだ
It's one of the most orthodox
and powerful styles.
Right now a drive would be effective.
今ならばドライブが有効な場面
だが 行けん
But he can't go.
うかつに切り込めば—
If he dives in carelessly, it's likely
he'll be caught by No. 11's steal.
11番のスティールに
捕まる可能性が極めて高い
If I pour my senses into a drive,
（笠松）ドライブに
全神経を注げば—
透明少年を かわすゆとりはねえ
I won't be able to avoid the invisible kid...
くそったれが…
Damn him!
単発じゃねえ 威嚇力がある
He has multiple threats.
His talons are the real deal!
猛きんの爪は だてじゃねえな
Senpai!
（黄瀬）先輩！
（木吉）やはり来たか
He's coming.
（笠松）ここで引くのは
不本意だが…
I don't want to back down now, but...
It's all you, ace!
頼むぜ エース！
This guy...
（黄瀬）こいつ…
エンジンかかってきた
みたいっスね
Looks like you're finally warmed up.
つーか 改めて向き合うと—
In fact...
Now that I'm facing you, I can tell
you're a totally different person now.
前とは別人じゃん
（黄瀬）フッ 面白(おもしれ)え
Interesting...
えいっ
I'll stop you!
（早川）止めう
うがっ
火神！
Kagami!
（誠凛部員たち）行けー！
Go!
He stopped the shot!
（観客１）止めた
（観客２）両エース 譲らねえ！
Neither ace is giving any ground!
（黄瀬･火神）ハァ
Senpai...
（火神）先輩
次もボールくれ… です
Give me the ball again, please.
Leave him to me.
（黄瀬）あいつは任せてほしいっス
（伊月）いよいよ火がついてきたな
He's finally warmed up.
Okay.
Sheesh. I can't refuse my
ace when he looks like this.
（笠松）ったく エースが
こんな面してたら断る理由がねえぜ
分かった
Fine.
（火神）次こそぶち抜く
（黄瀬）今度も止める
I'll break through this time.
I'll stop him again.
The tension is incredible.
（日向）すげえ 緊張感だ
まるで居合の達人が構えを取って
対じしているみてえだ
They're like master swordsmen facing off.
Hey, Satsuki.
（青峰）なあ さつき…
運命… ってもん信じるか？
Do you believe in destiny?
What?
何言ってんの？ 何言ってんの？
What are you talking about?
（青峰）熱なんかねえよ バカ！
I don't have a fever!
（青峰）柄にもねえのは
分かってるけどよ
I know it's out of character.
最近 ふと思うんだよ
But lately I've been thinking.
オレたち５人“キセキの世代”と
テツが同じ時期にそろったのは—
Was it really a coincidence that
the Generation of Miracles and Tetsu
単なる偶然なのかってよ
came together at the same time?
I don't know if it means anything.
意味があるかなんて
知るわけねえけどよ
It's just something I sense.
なんとなく感じるもんもある
同じチームにいたこと
その後 敵同士になったこと
We were on the same team.
Then we became enemies.
この大会で全員集まったこと
Recently we all made it to this tournament.
そんで 運命なんてもんが
もしあるなら—
If destiny does exist, then his
appearance must have been fate, too.
あいつがオレたちの前に
現れたことも
“キセキの世代”と
同じ存在でありながら—
One like the Generation of Miracles
that couldn't become one of us.
“キセキの世代”とは
ならなかったもの
“キセキの世代”と
同じ才能を持つ最後の覚醒者
The last awakened one with as much
talent as the Generation of Miracles.
キセキならざるキセキ
そして—
The Miracle that never was.
The...
運命の影と出会った—
...true light destined to meet his shadow.
真の光
（火神）うおおー えいっ
勝ち！
I win!
Damn you...
こんにゃろ
Preview
I won't be beat!
（早川）オエも負けあえん
イバウンドもそえ以外も
全部ぎゃおばっすよ
I'll do my best to get
rebounds and everything else!
（森山）落ち着け
何て言ったかさっぱりだ
Calm down!
I have no idea what you're saying!
No matter what happens,
I believe in Kaijo's ace, Kise!
（早川）にゃがっても海常お
エースの黄瀬をしんおうします！
Don't Underestimate Me!!
（森山）そうだな
オレたちも全力で支えるぞ
You're right.
Let's support him with everything we've got!
（早川）はい
Yes, sir!